Guide to the Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks, 1850s-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University, Durham, N.C., USA
- American Cookbooks 1940s, 9
  - Revere's Guide to Better Cooking, 1941 (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0041)
    Company: Revere Copper and Brass Inc.
    Product: Revere Copper Clad Stainless Steel Ware
    Note: black-and-white pictures, small orange and black illustrations
  - Wear-Ever…New Method Cooking Instruction Book, 1948 (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0043)
    Product: Wear-Ever aluminum pots and pans
  - 30 New Tested Nestlé's Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0044)
    Product: Nestlé's Evaporated Milk
    Note: small color illustrations
  - Borden's Eagle Brand magic Recipes, 1946 (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0045)
    Product: Borden's Eagle Brand Sweetened Condensed Milk
    Note: black-and-white pictures, hints, use of 'magic' slogan
  - Bright Ideas with Versatile Velveeta, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0046)
  - Cottage Cheese Surprises…40 Recipes for Meatless Meals…Delicious Desserts and 37 Salad Combinations, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0047)
    Company: Richmond Dairy Company
  - Flavored Milk Drinks… Nourishing and Easily Prepared, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0048)
  - New Sealtest Book of Recipes and Menus, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0050)
  - Quick, Easy, Recipes for 2 or 4 or 6, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0051)
    Note: by Mary Lee Taylor, color pictures, ad for The Mary Lee Taylor Program
  - SEGO Milk Flashes Double Header!, 1940 (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0052)
    Note: offer for Quality Table Set with SEGO Milk coupons, list of stores with SEGO milk
  - Tested Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0053)
    Note: pink, color illustrated cover
  - The Sealtest Food Adviser, 1940 (Box C06, Item 1940sC-0054)
    Product: Akron Pure Sealtest Milk
    Note: black-and-white and color pictures
  - The Sealtest Food Adviser, 1941 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0055)
    Note: black-and-white and color recipes, Sealtest recipe of the month, Importance of Milk by Dr. H.A. Ruehe
  - Try These Tasty Treats made with Borden's Creamed Cottage Cheese, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0056)
    Product: Borden's Creamed Cottage Cheese
  - Western Maryland Dairy Cook Book Kitchen Tested Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0057)
    Company: Western Maryland Dairy, Sealtest, Inc.
  - Why you should serve Hydrox Sealtest Ice Cream at Birthdays, Dinners, Bridge Parties, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0058)
    Company: Hydrox Ice Cream Company, Inc.
  - untitled, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0059)
    Product: Milk and Butter
    Note: two loose small pieces of paper with recipes, color pictures, and information on butter, milk, and puddings
  - 18 Recipes from Her Minute Movies, 1947 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0060)
    Note: front cover features Chiquita Banana in traditional garb, black-and-white photographs inside
  - For all occasions California Ripe Olives, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0061)
    Company: Ehmann Olive Company
    Product: Ehmann Ripe Olives
  - How to Make Life Sweeter with EVERBEST Preserves & Jellies, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0062)
    Company: EVERBEST Preserves
    Product: EVERBEST Preserves
    Note: black-and-white pictures, color illustrations, imitation wood cover and back
  - It All Depends on What You're Serving, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0063)
    Company: Tea Garden Products Company
    Product: Tea Garden Jellies and Preserves
  - Jane Withers, 'Oh Boy… Home-Made Ice Cream!', circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0064)
    Note: color pictures of desserts with recipes on back, cut-out on dotted line
  - New Variety for Low Carbohydrate Diets with D-Zerta, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0065)
    Product: D-Zerta
  - Sally Eilers says: These are my favorite desserts, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0066)
    Product: Royal Gelatin Dessert
  - What makes Jelly 'Jell?', 1945 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0067)
    Product: General Foods Canning
    Note: information on how to make jelly, jam, marmalade, black-and-white pictures
  - Nabisco 100% Bran Easy 7 Tasty Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0068)
    Product: Nabisco 100% Bran
  - Recipe for Vanilla Wafers Banana Pudding, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0069)
    Product: NBC Vanilla Wafers
  - Recipes for..., circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0070)
    Company: Nabisco Company
    Product: N.B.C. Soda Crackers
  - Recipes from Walton's Wonder Rice, 1949 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0071)
    Company: Walton Rice Mill, Inc.
    Product: Walton's Wonder Rice
    Note: letter to homemaker from Flora Adams, followed by recipes
  - Shredded Wheat the Vitally Different Food, Why Shredded Wheat is a Vitally Different Food, Eat Shredded Wheat the Vitally Different Food, Here is a Vitally Different food shredded wheat, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0072)
    Note: 6 pieces of cardboard with blue writing offering cut-out recipes
  - The Plus Food for Minus Meals, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0073)
    Product: Kellogg's All-Bran
    Note: color pictures, green theme, introduction by Barbara B. Brooks
  - What is Prince Enriched Pastina, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0074)
    Company: Prince Macaroni Company
    Product: Pastina
  - First Aid, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0075)
    Note: black-and-white illustrations of injury, index of health conditions
  - Cold Cooking, 1942 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0076)
  - Cook Book… O'Keefe & Merritt, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0077)
    Product: O'Keefe & Merritt Gas Ranges
    Note: Includes a Kerr canning time table
  - Electric Cooking with your Hotpoint Automatic Range, 1947 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0078)
    Company: Hotpoint, Inc.
  - How to use and enjoy your new Frigidaire Cold-Wall, 1947 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0079)
    Product: Frigidaire Cold-Wall refrigerator
  - Norge Cold Cookery and Recipe Digest, 1947 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0080)
    Product: Norge Refrigerators
    Note: cartoon of Eskimo-Refrigerator man
  - O'Keefe & Merritt Cook Book, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0081)
  - RobertShaw Oven Cookery Directions, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0082)
    Product: RobertShaw Automaticook
  - The Art of Broiling, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0083)
    Product: Spark Gas Range
    Note: published by the Manufacturers of Spark Gas Ranges, 25 cents, black-and-white pictures, green and orange cover
  - Your Westinghouse Refrigerator It's care and use over 100 delicious recipes, 1947 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0084)
    Note: introduction by Julia Kiene, black-and-white pictures, 25 cents
  - Fish and Shellfish Cookery made easy, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0085)
    Company: National Fisheries Institute Inc.
  - Meat Recipe Book Victory Meat Extenders, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0086)
    Note: black-and-white pictures and illustrations, pledge of American Homemakers on back (pic of statue of liberty)-in order to help the war, note to buy war bonds, red white blue theme
  - Meat The Main Course, 1942 (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0087)
    Note: color pictures, charts of cooking time and types of meat, list of Kingan's products
  - Menu Magic, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0088)
  - New for Easter… New Tenderness Tru-Ham Flavor Cooks in 25% Less Time, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0089)
    Product: Armour's Star Ham, Jubilee Ham, Star Lard, Vegetole
  - Tasty Meals and Snacks featuring Made-Rite Camellia Brand Prepared Meat Products, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0090)
    Company: Camellia
    Product: Camellia Ham, Bacon, Pork Sausage, Braunschweiger
  - The Lamb Menu Book, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0091)
    Product: Selected Lamb Recipes
    Note: black-and-white diagram of lamb on inside cover, pink pictures of meat throughout pamphlet
  - Variety Meats… Recipes for Heart, Liver, Kidney, Sweetbreads, Tongue, Tripe, Brains, circa 1940s (Box C07, Item 1940sC-0092)
  - 1, 000 Calory Diet, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0093)
    Company: Warner-Chilcott Laboratories Div.
  - 500 Delicious Dishes from Leftovers, get the most from the food you buy, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0094)
    Product: Culinary Arts Institute
    Note: black-and-white pictures, green cover with black-and-white pictures, fragile condition
  - 500 Snacks Bright Ideas for Entertaining, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0095)
    Note: loose front cover, no back cover, black-and-white pictures
  - An important supplement for your cook book from the Prudence Penny Home Makers' Dept., circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0096)
    Company: Prudence Penny
  - Food Standards Handbook for Quantity Cookery, 1943 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0097)
    Note: by J.O. Dahl and J.H. Breland, Gold Book Library, index of portion sizes
  - Tea Sandwiches, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0098)
    Company: American Home Kitchen
  - The Laundry Guide, 1946 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0099)
    Company: Automatic Washer Company
    Product: Automatic Washer Company
    Note: washing and ironing instructions with black-and-white photographs
  - 15 Appetite Tempters… Globe 'A1' Macaroni Spaghetti Noodles, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0100)
    Product: Globe 'A1' noodles, flour, sesame oil
  - Brer Rabbit All-Bran Muffins, Brer Rabbit All-Bran Brown Bread, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0101)
    Company: Kellogg Company and Brer Rabbit
    Product: Kellogg's All Bran, Brer Rabbit New Orleans Molasses
    Note: two small pieces of paper with color pictures and two recipes
  - Cake Secrets, 1941 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0102)
    Product: General Foods, Baking
    Note: color illustrations, offer for free Swans Down Cake Set, cover and back loose, fragile condition
  - Champion 'A1' Recipes… 30 Practical Globe 'A1' Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0103)
    Product: Globe 'A1' Flour, Cornmeal, Oil
  - Foremost…The Great Name in Dairy Products…Cook Book, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0104)
    Company: Foremost Dairies, Inc.
    Product: cottage cheese, light cream, sour cream, homogenized milk, buttermilk
  - Meatless Recipes with Meaty Flavors, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0105)
    Company: Madison Foods
    Product: Vigorost, Yum, Zoyburger, Stake-Lets, Not-Meat
  - Timely Recipes Starring Canned Foods, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0106)
    Company: Libby's 100 Famous Foods
  - Try these Dream Whip Ideas, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0107)
    Company: Walter Baker & Company, Jell-O Company
    Product: Dream Whip, Jell-O
  - Win New Cooking Fame with Diamond branded Walnuts, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0108)
  - 10 Luscious New Cakes, 1945 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0109)
    Product: Vegetable Shortening
    Note: Lever Golden Jubilee emblem, New Easy Mix good if low on sugar
  - 24 New Dressings for... 24 All-American Salads, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0110)
  - 6 Lucky Recipes, 1943 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0111)
    Company: Blue Bonnet
    Note: gray cover, features Blue Bonnet Sue, saves ration points
  - 6 Lucky Recipes, 1944 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0112)
    Note: red cover, features Blue Bonnet Sue, saves ration points
  - A Fluffy-Rich Golden Shortening that gives you--A New Kind of Cooking, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0113)
    Product: Fluffo
  - Aunt Jenny says…, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0114)
  - Aunt Jenny's Delicious Sure-Fire Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0115)
  - Aunt Jenny's Full Flavor Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0116)
  - Aunt Jenny's Old Home Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0117)
  - Good Cooking Made Easy, 1942 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0118)
    Note: Aunt Jenny on inside cover, picture of military men enjoying food, guaranteed by Good Housekeeping
  - How to Win Compliments for Your Cooking, 1949 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0119)
    Note: black-and-white photographs, color pictures, simple cartoons of happy family
  - Try Aunt Jenny's Favorite Cake, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0120)
  - All Electric-Mix Recipes, 1949 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0121)
    Product: Electric Food Mixer
    Note: stereotypical chef inside front cover, spokeswoman promise
  - Electric Popper Recipes Instructions, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0122)
    Company: U. S. Manufacturing Corporation
    Product: U.S. Electric Popper
  - How to Get the Most Out of Your Sunbeam Mixmaster, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0123)
    Product: Model 7B Automatic Mixmaster
  - Instructions and Appetizing Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0124)
    Company: Griscer Industries, Inc.
  - Instructions and Tested Recipes, 1948 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0125)
    Product: Food Mixer with Mix Guide
    Note: tested at Syracuse, vacuum ad in back
  - New! Kitchen Tested Recipes for Speedier Tastier Meals Automatic Fryer-Cooker, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0126)
    Product: automatic Fryer-Cooker
  - SpeeDrip makes better coffee Simple easy quick!, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0127)
    Product: SpeeDrip
  - There's Something New Inside the Toastmaster, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0128)
    Company: Toastmaster
    Product: Toaster
    Note: guarantees perfect toast with 'Flexible Clock'
  - Westinghouse tell-all-tag, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0129)
    Product: Roaster-Over De Luxe Model RO-81
  - Easy Ways to Good Meals…99 Delicious Dishes Made with Campbell's' Soups, 1941 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0130)
    Company: Campbell Soup Company
    Product: Campbell's Soup
    Note: envelope included, meal-planner's guide in back
  - Wilson's B-V Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0131)
    Product: Wilson's B-V
  - Delightful Uses for Cafecoco-Rico Syrup and Coffeerico Supreme, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0132)
    Product: Cafecoco-Rico, Coffeerico, Lemmix
  - Dessert Recipes… Golden Jubilee U and I Sugar, 1941 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0133)
    Company: U & I Sugar Corporation
    Product: U and I Sugar
  - Honey… A Good Cook's Secret, 1942 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0134)
    Company: John G. Paton Company, Inc.
    Product: Golden Blossom Honey
  - Kitchen tested Recipes featuring Spreckels wonderful Golden Brown Sugar, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0135)
    Company: Spreckels Sugar Company
    Product: Spreckels Golden Brown Sugar
  - Make your Precious Sugar go further with Grandma's Old Fashioned Molasses, 1945 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0136)
    Product: Old Fashioned Molasses
  - Sioux Bee Honey for Best Results in these Selected Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0137)
    Company: Sioux Honey Association
    Product: Sioux Bee Honey, Honey Crème
  - 500 Delicious Salads, 1940 (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0138)
    Note: color cover, black-and-white pictures inside
  - Menus…Recipes, circa 1940s (Box C08, Item 1940sC-0139)
    Company: Keystone Mushroom Company
    Product: Mushrooms
    Note: mushroom history and nutritional information in front
  - The Story of Dagger Jamaica Rum Including Selected Recipes, circa 1940s (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0001)
    Company: J. Wray & Nephew, Ltd.
    Product: Dagger rum
  - Learn to Bake…You'll Love it!, 1947 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0002)
  - Betty Crocker Chiffon Cake Recipes and Secrets, 1948 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0003)
  - Stretching Meat, circa 1943 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0004)
    Product: Gold Medal, Softasilk flour
    Note: Wartime ration points, Victory Garden articles
  - ABCs of Herb Cookery, 1941 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0005)
    Product: House of Herbs spices
  - Adventures in Herb Vinegars, 1946 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0006)
    Note: Irma Goodrich Mazza
  - Seasoning Tricks, 1945 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0007)
    Note: Patricia Winter
  - Adventures in Cake Craft, 1948 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0008)
    Product: Pillsbury's Best XXXX flour
    Note: Ann Pillsbury
  - Globe A-1 biscuit flour, circa 1949 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0009)
    Product: Globe A-1 biscuit flour
  - The Photo-Method for Bread Making, 1949 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0010)
    Note: Virginia Roberts
  - The Bread Basket, 1943 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0011)
  - Some of My Favorite Good Things to Eat, 1940 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0012)
    Note: Martha Lee Anderson
  - Biscuits and Biscuits Glorified, 1941 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0013)
  - Cakes to Cheer About, 1941 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0014)
  - A Guide to Royal Success in Baking, 1942 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0015)
  - New Foods, New Drinks with Canada Dry, circa 1940 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0016)
    Product: Canada Dry Ginger Ale
  - Recipes Meals Around the Clock, circa 1940s (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0017)
    Product: Kaffee Hag Coffee
  - Baker's Favorite Chocolate Recipes, 1943 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0018)
  - Hershey's Recipes, 1940 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0019)
  - Kisses for the Cook, circa 1940s (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0020)
    Product: Gulden's prepared mustard
  - Sunday Night Successes with Kraft Kitchen Fresh Mayonnaise Products, circa 1940s (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0021)
    Product: Kraft mayonnaise products
  - Wear-Ever New Cooking Method, 1945 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0022)
    Product: Wear-Ever pans
  - Complete in Every Respect, circa 1940s (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0023)
    Product: Mirro cookware
  - Mirro Cook Book, 1947 (Box D12, Item 1940sD-0024)
    Note: Laura Wilson
  - Recipes-Directions-Time Tables, 1949 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0025)
  - How To Save Time in Your Kitchen, 1941 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0026)
  - Recipe Book, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0027)
    Product: Presto Pressure Cookers
  - Aunt Chick's Pies, 1948 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0028)
    Company: Nettie McBirney
    Product: Crispy Crust Pie Pan, cookie-making utensils
    Note: Mrs. Samuel Pendleton McBirney, original copyright 1940
  - Instructions, Time Tables and Recipes, circa 1940s (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0029)
    Product: Maid of Honor pressure cooker
  - Recipes, 1949 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0030)
    Product: Flavo-Seal Waterless cookware
  - Growing Up With Milk, 1942 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0031)
  - Tested Milnot Recipes, 1946 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0032)
    Company: Carolene Products Company
    Product: Milnot filled milk
    Note: Mary Elizabeth Wright
  - Cottage Cheese Surprises, circa 1940s (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0033)
    Company: H. P. Hood Company
    Product: Hood's Creamed Cottage Cheese
  - The Romance of Cheese, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0034)
  - Any Meal, Any Day-For 2 or 4 or 6, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0035)
  - Food for Fitness for 2 or 4 or 6, 1942 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0036)
  - Recipes for Victory Lunch Box Meals, 1942 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0037)
  - New Sealtest Recipes, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0038)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor March-April, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0039)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Holiday Number, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0040)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Spring, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0041)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Summer, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0042)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Winter, 1940 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0043)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor May-June, 1941 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0044)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor July-August, 1941 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0045)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Holiday, 1941 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0046)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Winter, 1941 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0047)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor March-April, 1942 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0048)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Winter, 1942 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0049)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor July-August, 1944 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0050)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Winter, 1946 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0051)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Number 66, 1946 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0052)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor March-April, 1947 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0053)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Number 67, 1947 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0054)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Number 69, 1947 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0055)
  - Sealtest Food Advisor Number 72, 1948 (Box D13, Item 1940sD-0056)
  - Seald Sweet Cook Book, 1945 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0057)
    Company: Florida Citrus Exchange
    Product: Seald Sweet fruit
    Note: Mrs. Christine Frederick
  - Bananas How to Serve Them, 1940 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0058)
  - 20 Famous Cranberry Dishes from Famous American Eating Places, 1949 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0059)
  - Salads, Desserts, Pies, Candies, 1945 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0060)
  - Salads, Desserts, Pies, Candies, 1943 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0061)
  - Bright Spots for Wartime Meals: 66 Ration-Wise Recipes, 1944 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0062)
  - The Speed-Up Gelatine, circa 1940s (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0063)
  - Royal Recipe Parade, 1942 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0064)
  - Albers Victory Recipes, 1943 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0065)
    Product: Albers flour and grain products
    Note: Martha Hunt
  - Magic Menus with Mueller's, 1945 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0066)
  - The Housewife's Yearbook of American Homemaking, 1945 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0067)
    Product: Kellogg's cereals
  - Kraft Macaroni and Cheese Dinner Recipes for Quick Tasty Meals, circa 1940s (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0068)
    Product: Kraft Macaroni and Cheese
  - Nancy Pepper's Recipes, 1948 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0069)
    Note: Nancy Pepper Kitchen
  - Frozen Foods, 1948 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0070)
    Product: GE freezers
  - How to Use and Enjoy Your New Frigidaire Electric Range, 1949 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0071)
  - Electric Cookery, circa 1940s (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0072)
    Product: Wards Electric Range
  - Where The Best Cooking is Done, circa 1940s (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0073)
    Product: Perfection High Power Oil Stoves
  - Making the Most of Your Servel Electrolux, 1941 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0074)
  - Good Things to Eat and How to Cook Them, 1940 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0075)
  - Recipes Care Use, 1948 (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0076)
  - Westinghouse Kitchen-proved Economy and Econo-Cookers, circa 1940s (Box D14, Item 1940sD-0077)
  - Westinghouse Kitchen-proved Refrigerator Book, 1940 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0078)
  - Kingan's Meat Recipe Book, circa 1940s (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0079)
  - The State of Maine's Best Seafood Recipes, 1945 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0080)
    Company: Maine Department of Sea and Shore Fisheries
    Product: Maine seafood
  - Lamb Recipes Lamb for Goodness Sake, 1940 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0081)
    Company: National Wool Growers Association
  - 86 New Proven Tuna Recipes and the Romance of Tuna, 1940 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0082)
    Product: Chicken of the Sea canned tuna
    Note: Includes essay on tuna industry
  - 250 Fish and Sea Food Recipes, 1941 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0083)
  - American Woman's Food Stretcher Cook Book, 1943 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0084)
  - 250 Poultry Specialties, 1943 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0085)
    Company: Dell Publishing
  - How To Carve Your Turkey, circa 1940s (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0086)
    Company: Gulf Oil Company
    Product: Gulf Dealers
    Note: Duncan Hines
  - The Pocket Cook Book, 1942 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0087)
    Company: McCall's Magazine
    Note: Elizabeth Woody
  - 100 Meat Saving Recipes, 1943 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0088)
    Company: Thomas Y. Crowell Company
    Note: Ann Roe Robbins
  - Vanceboro's (North Carolina) Favorite Recipes, circa 1940s (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0089)
    Company: Women's Auxiliary of St. Paul's Episcopal Church
  - The Art and Secrets of Chinese Cookery, 1949 (Box D15, Item 1940sD-0090)
    Product: La Choy Chinese foods
  - Birds Eye Cook Book Tempting Recipes for Good Meals, 1941 (Box D16, Item 1940sD-0091)
    Product: Birds Eye frozen food
  - The Heinz Book of Quantity Recipes and Menus, 1940 (Box D16, Item 1940sD-0092)
  - An Important Supplement for Your Cookbook, circa 1940s (Box D16, Item 1940sD-0093)
    Company: New York American/Prudence Penny Home Maker's Dept.
  - Giving Your Meals The Touch of Individuality with Delicious Yeast Baked Breads, 1942 (Box D16, Item 1940sD-0094)
  - It's the Finish That Counts, 1949 (Box D16, Item 1940sD-0095)
    Product: Fleischmann products